Guide to the Oregon State Technical Record Engineering Magazine 1925-1959
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
Oregon State Technical Record Engineering Magazine
1925-1959
Oregon State College. School of Engineering.
PUB 010-15b
0.70 cubic feet 2 boxes
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The Oregon State Technical Record was written, edited, and published by engineering students at Oregon State College. The issues that comprise this archival collection are available online in Oregon Digital. All issues of the Oregon State Technical Record are available in the History of Oregon State University rare book collection. An index that includes references for the Technical Record and its predecessor, the Student Engineer, is available in the History of Oregon State University collection and online.
Historical Note:
The Oregon State Technical Record superseded the Student Engineer, which was published from 1908 to 1923.
The Oregon State Technical Record was establshed in 1924 with the aim of becoming a member of the Engineering College Magazines Associated which was attained in 1928 when the publication was admitted to membership of the association. A benefit of membership was being eligible to obtain national advertising to support the magazine's production. The Technical Record received several honors from the association in the 1930s. Publication was temporarily suspended in 1944 and 1945 during World War II. In 1948, the title became Oregon State Tech Record.
Publication ended with the May 1959 issue (v. 34, no. 4).
Oregon Agricultural College--Students.; Oregon Agricultural College. School of Engineering.; Oregon State Agricultural College--Students.; Oregon State College--Students.; Oregon State College. School of Engineering.
College students' writings, American--Oregon--Corvallis.; College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Engineering laboratories--Oregon--Corvallis.; Engineering schools--Oregon--Corvallis.; Engineering students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Engineering--Research--Oregon.; Engineering--Study and teaching (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.; Engineering--Periodicals.
Colleges and Universities; Science; Student Life; Technology; Oregon; Corvallis
These archival copies were received by the former University Archives in multiple transfers through the 1990s.
Collection is open for research.
The College of Engineering Records (RG 062), Photographs (P 061), and Moving Images (FV 061) provide extensive documentation of the engineering at Oregon State. Records of engineering departments as well as engineering student organizations and honor societies and materials created by engineering alumni are also available in the Special Collections and Archives Research Center.
The Co-Signers Engineer Students' Wives' Club Collection (MSS Cosigners) documents the perspectives and activities of the wives of engineering students from the late 1950s through 1970s.
The Oregon State Technical Record Engineering Magazine is arranged in one series.
The Oregon State Technical Record was written, edited, and published by engineering students at Oregon State College. It was initially published by the Federated Engineers of Oregon Agricultural College and then the Associated Engineers. Beginning in 1948, the undergraduate students of the School of Engineering were in charge of the publication.
During most of its existence, the magazine was published 4 times per academic year in November, January, March, and May. The magazine includes technical articles written by students, faculty, and alumni; information about engineering courses and research activities; announcements of student activities for engineering students; and articles about regional developments in industry, engineering, and technology. Campus news, especially regarding facilities and engineering topics; notices from the engineering technical and honor societies; and alumni news are also included. Most issues have a column written by the Dean of the School of Engineering and many have departmental notes and news. Editorials by the magazine staff address a variety of topics. The magazine is illustrated with photographs and includes a humor page as well as local, regional, and national advertising.
The issues that comprise this archival collection are available online in Oregon Digital. Most (about 80%) of the magazine issues are represented in this archival collection. The archival collection does not include the first 3 issues -- published in March, June and November 1924. These are are available, with all issues of the Oregon State Technical Record, in the History of Oregon State University rare book collection. An index that includes references for the Technical Record and its predecessor, the Student Engineer, is available in the History of Oregon State University collection and online.
- Oregon State Technical Record, 1925-1959; Series 1
  Series 1 consists of individual unbound issues of the Oregon State Technical Record.
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1925 - Nov. 1927 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 2, Number 2, January 1925 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 2, Number 3, March 1925 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 2, Number 4, May 1925 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 3, Number 1, December 1925 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 3, Number 4, May 1926 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 4, Number 1, November 1926 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 4, Number 2, February 1927 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 4, Number 3, March 1927 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 4, Number 4, May 1927 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Volume 5, Number 1, November 1927 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, February 1928 - November 1930 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 5, Number 2, February 1928 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 5, Number 3, March 1928 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 5, number 4, May 1928 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 6, Number 2, February 1929 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 6, Number 3, March 1929 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 6, Number 4, May 1929 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 7, Number 1, November 1929 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 7, Number 2, February 1930 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 7, Number 3, March 1930 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 7, Number 4, May 1930 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Volume 7, Number 4, November 1930 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1931- November 1932 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 8, Number 1, January, 1931 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 8, Number 2, March 1931 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 8, Number 3, May 1931 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 9, Number 1, January 1932 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 9, Number 2, March 1932 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Volume 9, Number 3, May 1932 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Campus Edition, November 1932 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1933 - November 1936 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - January 1933 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - March 1933 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - May 1933 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Issue, January 1934 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Engineering Research Issue, March 1934 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - January 1936 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - March 1936 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - May 1936 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - November 1936 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, May 1937 -November 1939 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Tech Record, May 1937 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 15, Number 1, November 1937 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 15, Number 2, January 1938 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 15, Number 3, March 1938 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 15, Number 4, May 1938 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 16, Number 1, November 1938 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 16, Number 2, January 1939 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 16, Number 3, March 1939 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 16, Number 4, May 1939 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Volume 17, Number 1, November 1939 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1940 - November 1941 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 17, Number 2, January 1940 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 17, Number 3, March 1940 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 17, Number 4, May, 1940 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 18, Number 1, November 1940 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 18, Number 2, January 1941 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 18, Number 3, April 1941 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 18, Number 4, May 1941 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Volume 19 Number 1, November 1941 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Oregon State Technical Records, January 1942 - December 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Volume 19, Number 2, January 1942 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Volume 19, Number 3, March 1942 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Volume 19, Number 4, May 1942 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, November 1942 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, January 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, March 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, May 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, August 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
    - Tech Record, December 1943 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, November 1946 - November 1947 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Volume 22, Number 1, November 1946 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Volume 22, Number 2, March 1947 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Volume 22, Number 3, May 1947 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Volume 23, Number 1, November 1947 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1948 - November 1949 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 23, Number 2, January 1948 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 23, Number 3, March 1948 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 23, Number 4, May 1948 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 24, Number 1, November 1948 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 24, Number 2, January 1949 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 24, Number 3, March 1949 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Volume 25, Number 1, November 1949 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Volume 24, Number 4, May 1949 (Box-folder 2.3)
    This issue is falling apart, that is why it is in a folder by itself.
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1950 - November 1951 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Volume 25, Number 2, January 1950 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Volume 25, Number 3, March 1950 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, May 1950 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, November 1950 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, January 1951 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, March 1951 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, May 1951 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - Tech Record, November 1951 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1952 - November 1954 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, January 1952 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, May 1952 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, November 1952 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, November 1953 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, January 1954 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, March 1954 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, May 1954 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Tech Record, November 1954 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, January 1955 - November 1956 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, January 1955 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, May 1955 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, November 1955 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, January 1956 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, March 1956 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, May 1956 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Tech Record, November 1956 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Oregon State Technical Record, May 1957 - May 1959 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, May 1957 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, November 1957 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, January 1958 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, March 1958 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, November 1958 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, January 1959 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Tech Record, May 1959 (Box-folder 2.7)